https://www.charlestonsouthern.edu/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
HOME > Privacy Policy
Who we are
The following information discloses the manner in which Charleston Southern University collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users of the www.charlestonsouthern.edu site and all subsites (e.g., MyCSU).
Personal identification information
Charleston Southern University may collect personal identification information from users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when users visit this site, register on the site, subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on this site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, phone number. Users may, however, visit our site anonymously by not giving personal identification information on forms. We will collect personal identification information from users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users may always refuse to supply personally identifying information, understanding that it may prevent them from accessing site-related activities.
Applicants and Prospective Students
Charleston Southern University collects and uses personal information about applicants and other prospective students, including students interested in our summer programs (referred to collectively as applicants). If you are or have been an applicant, we may collect and use the following types of personal information about you:
Information and supporting documentation that you provide in your application, including through third partiesRelated application materials (e.g., recommendations, references, and test scores)Information that you have permitted a third party, such as The College Board, to release (e.g., AP or PSAT scores, demographic information, academic information)Contact information for prospective students that we receive from our service providers or vendors who conduct marketing, recruiting, or advertising activities for usFinancial information (e.g., information collected in connection with applications for financial aid, loans, and scholarships)Survey responses (if you choose to respond to a survey sent by us or on our behalf)
Your personal information is used primarily for our legitimate interests in evaluating your application and related activities, such as evaluating requests for financial aid, communicating with you about your application, and other administrative functions related to the admissions and enrollment process.
We may also use or disclose your personal information for the following purposes, based on our legitimate interests:
For compliance with legal obligationsTo consider requests for accommodationsFor research and statistical purposesTo provide you with information about Charleston Southern University and events that you might be interested in attending
We may share your information with the following individuals and entities:
Individuals who assist in the application process, such as faculty and outside consultantsGovernment agencies as necessary for compliance with law (e.g., for international students in the immigration process)Other departments within the universityYour financial institutions and funders (e.g., as necessary for obtaining loans, scholarships, or other funding)Other educational institutions (e.g., in order to send you information about jointly hosted informational events)Service providers or vendors who provide services to Charleston Southern University
Students and Employees
When you are a student at Charleston Southern University, or a member or prospective member of the faculty and staff, we maintain records containing your personal information. We may collect and use the following types of personal information about you, as applicable:
Your contact information and biographical data (e.g., name, address, date of birth, race, ethnicity)Application materials and supporting documents (e.g., applications for admission or employment)Copies of identification documents and other official documents (e.g. driver’s license, I-9 form, passport/visa information)Employment and/or educational records (e.g., job history, job reviews, transcript information)Academic work product and related information (e.g., research and course-related content)Records about your other activities (e.g., involvement in clubs, disciplinary actions and similar incidents)Financial information (e.g., payroll information, information related to tuition payments)Certain health information (e.g., disabilities, allergies)Information about technology usage (e.g., IP addresses, software downloads)
We use this information for the following purposes necessary for your student or employment relationship with Charleston Southern University, as well as for our other legitimate interests:
To provide educational, employment and/or related services (e.g., maintaining relevant records of your studies or employment, providing you with access to facilities and support services, such as counseling and IT services)To administer the financial aspects of the relationship (e.g., payroll, collecting tuition, coordinating with lenders or other funders)To enable your participation at events and in other opportunities (e.g., graduation, study abroad programs, internships)To protect the safety and health of you, other students, faculty, staff, and visitors and to protect the educational integrity of the school (e.g., security operations, disciplinary actions, assistance in the event of an emergency)To accommodate special needs (e.g., disability accommodations)For research and statistical purposes related to our educational and/or related servicesTo fulfill our responsibilities under applicable law (e.g., employer obligations, immigration, Title IX)To provide basic contact information in student, faculty, and/or staff directories
Alumni and Supporters
Charleston Southern University holds personal information related to its alumni and other supporters (such as donors, prospective donors, volunteers and family members of students). If you are an alum or other supporter, we may collect and use the following types of personal information about you:
Academic information (e.g., major, transcript, degree)Biographical information (e.g., name, date of birth, ethnicity, gender, religious affiliation)Contact information (e.g., email address, phone number)Your activities at Charleston Southern University (e.g., club memberships)Your involvement with Charleston Southern University and other interests (e.g., attendance at events, philanthropic interests)Family information (e.g., marital status, name of spouse)Health information (e.g., disability, food allergies)Financial information (e.g., history of donations, wealth information)Employment information
We collect data about alumni and other supporters from various sources, including directly from the individual (for example, by filling out a form on our website). We also retain information from your student records if you studied here. We also collect information from publicly available sources, such as social media, and from third parties, such as companies that conduct wealth screening or other people that might know you and your philanthropic interests.
Your personal information is used to provide you with certain alumni services, and for our legitimate interests in maintaining alumni relationships and conducting fundraising activities, including:
Sending you informational publications (e.g., CSU Magazine, newsletters from departments and clubs you may have interest in)Conducting surveys so that we can learn more about our alumni and other supportersProviding services (e.g., ongoing career services)Sending you information about fundraising campaigns, events and volunteer opportunities that may be of interest to youConducting wealth analysis and research to understand your philanthropic interests and ability to give in order to ensure that our fundraising efforts are tailored to your interestsFor administrative purposes (e.g., processing donations and issuing a tax receipt, managing events, such as reunions)For research and statistical purposesTo publicly acknowledge gifts (with consent of the donor)To meet legal obligations
With discretion, we may share your personal information with the following:
Charleston Southern University departments, clubs, and interest groupsThe Charleston Southern University Alumni AssociationOther CSU alumni – your consent will be requested before any information is shared with another alumnusThird parties engaged by Charleston Southern University to assist with the activities listed above
Nonpersonal identification information
Charleston Southern University may collect nonpersonal identification information about users whenever they interact with this site. This may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information, such as the operating system and the URL of the website from which you came and the URL you visit next, and other similar information.
Web browser cookies and tracking pixels
This site may use cookies to enhance user experience. A user’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. Users may disable cookies by adjusting the settings in the web browser, or users may choose to be alerted when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of this site may lack full functionality.
This site may also use tracking pixels to track conversions and activities. A pixel is loaded on the site when a user visits a web landing page and is used to acquire data for online marketing and web analysis.
How we use collected information
Charleston Southern University may collect and use personal information for the following purposes:
To provide services and to serve other university needsTo improve servicesTo personalize user experienceTo improve this siteTo run a promotion, contest, survey or other site featureTo send information agreed to by the user to receive about topics of interestTo send communication to current students, prospective students (or families), alumni and supporters
We may use your email address to respond to inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If a user decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include university news, updates, related educational or service information, etc. If at any time the user would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.
How we protect your information
Charleston Southern University adopts appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on this site.
Sharing your personal information
Charleston Southern University does not sell, trade, or rent personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted service providers and vendors for the purposes outlined above. We may use third party service providers to help us operate the university and this site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.
Third party websites
Users may find content on this site that links to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. Charleston Southern University does not have responsibility for the contents, availability, operation or performance of any other linked sites. Any reference to third parties by name, trademark or otherwise does not imply endorsement or recommendation by Charleston Southern University. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and constituent service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to this site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies.
Changes to this privacy statement
Charleston Southern University has the discretion to update this privacy statement at any time. The updated date is located at the bottom of this page. We encourage users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect personal information. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy statement periodically and become aware of modifications.
Your acceptance of these terms
By accessing or using this site, you signify your acceptance of this statement and terms of service. If you do not agree to this, please do not use this site. Your continued use of the site following the posting of changes to this statement will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.
Contacting us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or this site, please contact:
Office of Marketing and CommunicationCharleston Southern UniversityPO Box 118087Charleston, SC 29423
843-863-7606media@csuniv.edu
This privacy policy was last updated on June 1, 2018.
